Jah Caffie-Speed

732.881.4134

jahc.speed@gmail.com



Somerset, NJ



JahC.Speed

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Revolutionary and tech-savvy professional with solid experience managing projects within time, budget, and scope to drive efficiency, accuracy, and revenue. Strong business acumen leveraged to recommend solid improvements and implement highly technical activities seamlessly, fixing around 100 bugs in the first few weeks of tenure. Talent for forging relationships with colleagues, external stakeholders, and leadership to push projects to completion. Provides overall project management and coordination with technical teams using effective prioritization strategies.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Project Management ● Technical Aptitude ● Proactive Communication ● Cross-functional Collaboration ● Issue Resolution

CAREER SUMMARY -

Geek Squad

Geek Squad Technician

Bridgewater, NJ | 2024 - Present

As a Geek Squad Technician, I excel in being a technology superhero for our customers. I specialize in diagnosing and resolving hardware and software issues across a variety of devices, including computers, smartphones, and home entertainment systems. My primary goal is to provide exceptional customer service by offering expert advice and personalized recommendations tailored to meet each customer's unique needs. I pride myself on my ability to effectively troubleshoot and resolve technical challenges, earning consistent praise from customers for my professionalism and expertise. My track record speaks volumes. Within my position, I've soared to new heights, achieving milestones that set the standard for excellence:

- As the second highest seller of our esteemed Best Buy Total membership, I've demonstrated an innate talent for showcasing the value of our comprehensive service offerings.
- With a relentless dedication to efficiency, I've earned the distinction of creating and closing the most service tickets, ensuring that no technical challenge goes unresolved.
- Achieved an average customer satisfaction rating of 4.8 out of 5, based on post-service surveys, consistently exceeding departmental benchmarks.

Crimsonpvp Remote | 2023 - Present

Java Developer

Managed complex projects from inception to completion such as the creation of custom Minecraft mods and plugins, enhancing game performance, player engagement, and revenue objectives. Collaborated cross-functionally to resolve issues and push key initiatives forward, communicating proactively with designers and artists, to align development efforts with the game's overarching design and vision. Applied technical expertise to oversee new projects weekly including an open source/community built feature to create new features easily and seamless integration with other features.

Deployed speed, accuracy, and creative problem-solving to fix around 100 bugs in the first few weeks.

POSITION HIGHLIGHTS

Managed complex technical projects with impactful results.

- Drove user engagement with the successful implementation of Perks Plug-in, allowing new developers to easily create new perks while shaving off 10 to 12 hours each perk.
- Championed technical improvements, slashing at least two days of downtime by updating features to a current standard, drastically reducing the amount of overall RAM plugins were pulling, and utilizing newer features.

Signet Jewelers Remote | 2022

Digital Product Intern

Tapped for the role due to academic success to support the development cycle, defining requirements, collaborating with different teams, and analyzing customer experiences to inform the product strategy. Gained valuable real-world experience by applying technical expertise to create user stories based on the old clienteling application, rejuvenating app to a user-friendly version.

Project ManagementInnovative Solutions OutdatedTechnologiesInefficiencies

• Stakeholder Engagement Redundancy

Digital Product Intern (continued)

- Gained experience in agile ceremonies and grooming user stories, as
 well as the ability to communicate with stakeholders across different parts of the business.
- Honed communication and collaboration skills with an emphasis on proactive communication and active listening.
- Contributed to long-term company goals by executing Agile ceremonies, implementing standup meetings, working with developers, designers, and US teams, and leveraging a strong business acumen to recommend client solutions.

Schwifty Client Remote | 2020 – 2022

Java Developer

Built business from the ground up to deliver technical projects within time, budget, and quality goals such as decompiling the source files to the popular videogame "Minecraft," while making modifications to

the game based on user input.

 Grew a community of over 1,000 users with over 400 paid consumers of the application.

- Learned new technologies quickly while deploying Java, JUnit Testing Framework, external APIs, Maven (for individual dependencies microservices), and SQL.
- Spearheaded scripting feature to record players' movements in games and allowed players to repeat repetitive tasks and replay scripts they made, creating looping actions with one click.

EDUCATION

BA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Rutgers University **2023**

QUOTE/RECOMMENDATION

Jah became an essential part of the team, learning fast and delivering excellent results with ease."

QUOTE/RECOMMENDATION

"When given a task Jah finds the best way to tackle said task and communicates well to ensure requirements are being delivered in a timely manner."